In this episode we start to get a little bit closer to a full buffer overflow.
在这一集中，我们开始有所收获 更接近完整的缓冲区溢出。
In the last episode we have learned how a Buffer Overflow can change local variables,
在上一集中，我们学会了如何 缓冲区溢出可以更改局部变量，
which are stored on the stack.
它们存储在堆栈中。
Now we will have a look at stack level 3, which is very similar.
现在我们来看看堆栈级别3， 这是非常相似的。
If you forgot how we were able to solve stack level 0, you should go back and watch it again.
如果你忘记了我们如何解决堆栈问题 等级0，你应该回去再看一遍。
When we look at this code, we see that it is basically the same.
当我们查看此代码时，我们会看到它 基本相同。
The only difference is the name, instead of a modified variable, we have the fp variable,
唯一的区别是名称，而不是 一个修改过的变量，我们有fp变量，
which is defined as a function pointer.
它被定义为函数指针。
The syntax looks a bit ugly, but if you check the if case, it simply checks if fp is not
语法看起来有点难看，但是如果你检查一下 如果是这种情况，它只是检查fp是否不是
zero, and then just calls fp, as if it were a function.
零，然后只是调用fp，就好像它一样 一个功能。
Now you know that a function has an address location in memory.
现在你知道一个函数有一个地址 记忆中的位置。
So it will basically call whatever address is stored in fp.
所以它基本上会调用任何地址 存储在fp中。
Now like the modified variable in stack0, the function pointer fp gets set to 0 and
现在像stack0中的修改变量一样 函数指针fp设置为0和
after the gets function it will be checked if it’s not zero anymore.
在获取功能之后，它将被检查 如果它不再是零。
So we know that fp must also be stored on the stack.
所以我们知道fp也必须存储在 堆栈。
As a hint it says, that we can use gdb or objhump to determine where the win() function
作为提示它说，我们可以使用gdb或 objhump确定win（）函数的位置
lies in memory.
在于记忆。
So first let’s use gdb and you can use examine or print to get the address of win.
首先让我们使用gdb，你可以使用检查 或打印以获取胜利的地址。
Then set the disassembly flavor to intel and disassemble main.
然后将反汇编风格设置为intel和 拆卸主体。
Exactly like stack0, we can see that it makes space for hex 60 bytes on the stack.
完全像stack0，我们可以看到它 堆栈上六角形60字节的空间。
Then we set esp offset 5c to 0, so that is the location of the fp variable.
然后我们将esp offset 5c设置为0，这样就可以了 fp变量的位置。
After the gets, we compare the value if it is still 0 and if that were not the case,
获得之后，我们比较它的值 仍然是0，如果不是这样，
we load the value into eax down here, and call that address.
我们在这里将值加载到eax中，并且 叫那个地址。
So let’s set a breakpoint at this call.
所以让我们在这次通话中设置一个断点。
Now execute it and enter enough characters to overwrite this value on the stack.
现在执行它并输入足够的字符 覆盖堆栈上的这个值。
Exactly like last video.
完全像上一个视频。
Ok we hit the breakpoint, let’s look at the registers, and we can see, that we have
好的，我们打破了断点，让我们来看看 寄存器，我们可以看到，我们有
succesfully set eax to 41414141, which is the ascii value of capital A.
成功地将eax设置为41414141，这是 资本A的ascii值。
And the next instruction tries to call this address.
并且下一条指令试图调用它 地址。
So basically jump there.
所以基本上跳到那里。
But that is obviously invalid memory, se we get a Segmentation fault.
但那显然是无效的记忆，我们 得到分段错误。
Now open a second ssh session.
现在打开第二个ssh会话。
And create a python script, that will be our exploit.
并创建一个python脚本，这将是我们的 利用。
So let’s first try to figure out which offset controls eax.
所以让我们首先尝试找出哪个偏移量 控制eax。
So simply print a recognizable pattern.
因此，只需打印一个可识别的模式。
For example the alphabet.
例如字母表。
Ok. cool.
好。
So pipe this output in a file.
凉。
Now you can use this file in gdb as input.
因此，将此输出传递到文件中。
So we dont have to type it everytime, it will use the content of that file as input.
现在您可以在gdb中将此文件用作输入。 所以我们不必每次都输入它，它会
Now “run” and use the arrow left to redirect the file contents in the standard-input of
使用该文件的内容作为输入。 现在“运行”并使用左箭头重定向
the program.
标准输入中的文件内容
Ok so eax it’s hex 51, and that is a capital Q.
该程序。 好吧，所以eax它是十六进制51，这是一个资本
So now we know which offset modifies eax.
Q.
let’s rewrite the code a little bit.
所以现在我们知道哪个偏移修改了eax。
Let’s call this part up to the “Qs” - padding.
让我们重写一下代码。 让我们把这部分称为“Qs”
So now we want to write here the address of the win function.
- 填充。 所以现在我们要写这里的地址
So simply use backslash x as hex escape for those byte values.
胜利功能。 因此，只需使用反斜杠x作为十六进制转义
Oh oops.
那些字节值。
That doesn fit.
哦，哎呀。
There is a leading 0 missing.
那不合适。
Save, write the file.
有一个领先的0失踪。
And check it in gdb.
保存，写入文件。
Huh?
并在gdb中检查它。
segementation fault?
咦？
The address looks a bit weird.
分裂错？
Looks like it’s the wrong way around?
地址看起来有点奇怪。
Well, that is because of the endianess.
那是因为结束了。
So the numerical value will be basically the other way around.
所以数值基本上就是 其他方式。
cool.
凉。
Eax looks fine now.
Eax现在看起来很好。
let’s continue and we get code flow successfully changed!
让我们继续，我们成功地获得代码流 变了！
Now let’s quickly solve the next level as well.
现在让我们快速解决下一个级别 好。
This level is our first buffer overflow, where we take advantage of the stack layout.
这个级别是我们的第一个缓冲区溢出，其中 我们利用堆栈布局。
The code doesn’t contain much.
代码不多。
There is no function pointer variable we could overwrite.
我们没有函数指针变量 覆盖。
And now modified variable.
现在修改了变量。
But it still wants us to execute win.
但它仍然希望我们执行胜利。
So how do we do that?
那我们该怎么做呢？
Now do you remember how the stack looks like from last video?
现在你还记得堆栈的样子吗？ 从上一个视频？
Here is a quick recap:
这是一个快速回顾：
So here on the left you can see the assembler code.
所以在左边你可以看到汇编程序 码。
And on the right I will illustrate the stack. with the 3 important registers, the instruction
在右边，我将说明堆栈。 与3个重要的寄存器，指令
pointer EIP, the stack pointer ESP and the base pointer EBP.
指针EIP，堆栈指针ESP和 基指针EBP。
So first it starts somewhere else with a ‘call main’.
所以首先它通过'呼叫从其他地方开始 主要'。
Call will push the theoretically next instruction pointer onto the stack.
调用将推动理论上的下一条指令 指针到堆栈上。
And then jump to our main function.
然后跳转到我们的主要功能。
As you can see, when the address of the next instruction was pushed, the stack pointer
如你所见，当下一个地址 指令被推，堆栈指针
got incremented and the address placed there.
得到增加，地址放在那里。
So now comes our push EBP.
所以现在我们推动EBP。
How do we now know where to return to from main?
我们现在怎么知道从哪里返回 主要？
Well if you remember, call pushed the address of the instruction after the call.
好吧，如果你还记得，打电话推了一下地址 通话后的指令。
So the next value on the stack is where we want to return to.
所以堆栈的下一个值就是我们所处的位置 想回去。
And the ret instruction is basically just popping this address into the instruction
ret指令基本上就是 将此地址弹出到指令中
pointer.
指针。
And thus jumping back where we came from.
从而跳回我们来自的地方。
So as you can see, when a function is called, the address where we want to return to, will
正如您所看到的，当调用函数时， 我们想要回到的地址，将会
be stored on the stack.
存储在堆栈中。
So instead of overflowing a local variable, we can simply overflow the return pointer
所以不是溢出局部变量， 我们可以简单地溢出返回指针
on the stack.
在堆栈上。
And when main would return, it would read the wrong value and jump there instead.
当主要回来时，它会读 错误的值而是跳到那里。
So let’s use the code that we have just written, and modify it a bit.
所以让我们使用我们刚才拥有的代码 写了，稍微修改一下。
Let’s make the payload a bit longer and simply throw it at this program in gdb.
让我们使有效载荷更长一些 简单地把它扔在gdb中的这个程序中。
Segmentationfault in hex 54, so we succsefully redirected code execution, to bad memory.
分裂错误在十六进制54，所以我们succsefully 重定向代码执行，到坏内存。
And if you look closely you can also spot that the basepointer is hex 53.
如果仔细观察，你也可以发现 basepointer是十六进制53。
So that one was also overwritten, because if you remember from last video, the old basepointer
因此，一个人也被覆盖了 如果你记得上一个视频，旧的basepointer
is also stored on the stack, right before the instruction pointer.
之前也存储在堆栈中 指令指针。
And hex 54 is T. So T allows us to control
并且hex 54是T.所以T允许我们控制
This time let’s use objdump to find the address of the win function.
这次让我们用objdump找到 胜利功能的地址。
With -t we get all symbols, and then we can grep for win.
用-t我们得到所有符号，然后我们就可以 赢得胜利。
So there is our address.
所以有我们的地址。
Now let’s modify our exploit code.
现在让我们修改我们的漏洞利用代码。
Let’s remove everything up to the S, because that is the base pointer.
让我们删除一切到S的所有内容，因为 这是基指针。
Now create two variables ebp and eip.
现在创建两个变量ebp和eip。
We don’t care about EBP so we can just set it to whatever we want.
我们不关心EBP所以我们可以设置 它到我们想要的任何东西。
And next we want to set the instruction pointer.
接下来我们要设置指令指针。
But let me show a better way to encode the address as a string.
但是让我展示一种更好的编码方式 地址为字符串。
So import struct.
所以导入结构。
And then you can use struct.pack, to convert the address from the integer number into a
然后你可以使用struct.pack进行转换 地址从整数到a
binary string.
二进制字符串
Then print the padding and append the ebp and eip variable.
然后打印填充并附加ebp 和eip变量。
so let’s execute this exploit and pipe it into the stack4 level.
所以让我们执行这个漏洞并管道它 进入stack4级别。
Codeflow was successfully changed!
Codeflow已成功更改！
Amazing.
惊人。
We smashed the stack and controlled the instruction pointer.
我们粉碎了堆栈并控制了指令 指针。
But you still get a segementation fault?
但是你仍然会出现分裂错误？
The reason for that is, that after the win function is complete, it tries to return to
原因是，胜利之后 功能完成后，它会尝试返回
the next value on the stack, which is now some gibberish, and likely not in a valid
堆栈上的下一个值，现在是 一些胡言乱语，可能不是有效的
code area.
代码区。
So it will crash eventually.
所以它最终会崩溃。
But we don’t care, because we executed what we wanted.
但我们不在乎，因为我们执行了什么 我们要。
In the next video we will write our first buffer overflow with shellcode, which will
在下一个视频中，我们将首先编写 缓冲区溢出shellcode，将会
show you how powerful a buffer overflow can be.
向您展示缓冲区溢出有多强大 是。
And it will be our first exploit that will get us root privileges.
这将是我们的第一次利用 获得root权限。